Women of Rock Oral History Project oral histories
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- Tanya Pearson interview with Mary Timony, 2014 December 28
  In this oral history, Mary Timony discusses her childhood in Washington, D.C. and her interest in music from a young age. She details her high school and college experience, including the music scene in Washington, D.C. in the early 1990s and how her participation in the musical community helped to curb her social anxiety. Timony recalls her college career, the formation of her band, Helium, and what led to their disbandment. She discusses her musical output, collaborations, relationships and some of the double standards that women rock musicians face.
  Mary Timony (b. 1970) is a multi-instrumentalist who founded the band Autoclave in Washington D.C. and gained greater recognition as singer and guitarist in the Boston, Massachusetts band, Helium in the mid 1990s. Timony has released two solo albums and collaborated with a number of musicians on outside projects throughout her career. In 2011, she formed Wild Flag with members of Sleater Kinney and released an album before forming the critically acclaimed Ex Hex in 2014. When she's not touring, Timony teaches guitar lessons in Washington, D.C.
  A redacted version of this oral history is available at the Smith College Special Collections reading room. The full version will be available in 2055.